Curriculum Vitae

Ronald Pieterse Brouwersplein 40 2013 PH Haarlem

mobile: +31 (0)6 41373596

email: ronald@ahrendee.com

web: <u>ahrendee.com</u>

date of birth: 19 december 1970

nationality: Dutch

Profile

Fast-learning, autodidact, professional, drives for result.

Passionate for new technologies. Problem solver with good interpersonal skills. Always looking for new challenges and new technologies to learn.

Real teamplayer, working in scrum teams for many years.

After so many years of mostly back-end development I am expanding my knowledge more to full-stack Javascript with the focus on Typescript with Angular 7+, NodeJS, Express, MongoDB.

Meanwhile keeping up with latest features in Java 8 and Java 11

Built microservices with NodeJS and Spring Boot with Spring REST, deployed on various cloud services e.g. Github Pages, Heroku and PCF (Pivotal Cloud Foundry).

Working experience

Juli 2020 – present : Java developer at TNO GD&IT

Project: Working on the BRO application (former DINO application)

Technologies: Java 8 / 11, Webservices (REST / SOAP), Swagger-UI, Docker, ReadyAPI, Quarkus, RestEasy, MapStruct, RestAssured, Mockito.

March 2020 - present : Full-stack developer for augustlife.nl

Project: Building the full stack for the website of rock band August Life (http://augustlife.nl)

Front-end: Angular 9, TypeScript, HTML5, SCSS, deployed on Github Pages. Including custom built webshop with Paypal and IDeal payment functionality.

Back-end: NodeJS, Express, Rest API with JWT (JSON Web Tokens), Deployed on Heroku

Database: Cloud MongoDB (Atlas)

September 2017 - March 2020 : Lead front-end developer at Rabobank

Setting up and working on cards (debit-/credit) applications in Payments area in the monorepo of the platform Senses 2. Also mentoring newer front-end developers from India and the Netherlands.

Project: Apple Pay responsive front-end - Front-end development using Angular JS, Angular 8 and Ionic. Test framework CodeceptJS and Karma with Wiremock API mock system.

Project: Productservices Cards - Front-end development using AngularJS, Angular 8 and Ionic.

Technologies: Technologies I worked with include Angular 8+, Ionic, Angular JS, Node JS, NPM, Yarn, SCSS, Gulp, Grunt, Java, Spring Boot, Azure, PCF, Docker, Jenkins, Sonar, Swagger.

June 2017 - August 2017: Front-end developer at Prospery

Project: Prospery – Short running project for a Marketing website

Technologies: Technologies include NodeJS, NPM, Less, Sass, Gulp, HTML, Javascript, CSS.

March 2017 - May 2017 : Software Engineer at Kadaster

Project: KOERS - Frontend development

Technologies: Technologies include Angular (v1.5), Typescript, ES6, Webpack, NodeJS, HTML, Javascript, CSS.

Other technologies and Frameworks include Maven, Git, GitHub, JIRA, IntelliJ, Karma, Protractor.

October 2016 - February 2017: Software Engineer at ING

Project: Savings (Open&Close) / Digital 2.0

Technologies: Technologies include Polymer, AngularJS, NodeJS, HTML, Javascript, CSS, Java and Spring-REST and Spring-WS.

Other technologies and Frameworks include Maven, Git, Junit, Mockito, IntelliJ, Gulp, Grunt, Jasmine, Karma, Sinon, Protractor.

July 2015 - September 2016 : Software Engineer at Rabobank

Project: SABA - requesting and discontinuing accounts, creditcards, etc for businesses online and local Rabobank branches.

Technologies: Technologies include AngularJS, NodeJS, HTML, Javascript, CSS, Freemarker, Velocity as well as Java, Spring Webservices, Spring REST, Hibernate, JPA and Spring Security. Other technologies and Frameworks include Maven, Git, SVN, Jenkins, Sonar, Junit, Mockito, IntelliJ, Gulp, Grunt, Jasmine, Karma, Protractor, XML, JSON.

February 2015 - June 2015 : Software Engineer at DTG

Project: detelefoongids.nl

Technologies: Java, Freemarker, together with GWT, HTML, javascript and CSS. On the backend mainly Java; SEO data aggregation is done using Solr, the search engine/indexing platform. Aggregated data is stored in MongoDB.

Other technologies include Maven, SVN, Jenkins.

August 2014 – January 2015 : Software Engineer at UWV

Project: Digitalization dismissal process.

Technologies: Frontend technologies include NodeJS, AngularJS, Brunch and Bower, together with HTML and CSS. At the front- and backend the latest versions of Spring MVC, Spring Web-Flow, REST webservices and Oracle DB. Other technologies include Maven, SVN, Git, Jenkins.

September 2013 - June 2014 : Software Engineer at KLM (Royal Dutch Airlines)

Project: EBT / Search.

I worked in the EBT-AM scrum team, the maintenance team for the *Electronic Booking Tool* web application and secondly in the Search web application team (www.klm.com/home/nl/nl). Both teams worked according to the TDD principle.

Technologies: On the backend the latest versions of Spring MVC, Hibernate, Groovy, SOAP and REST webservices and so on. On the frontend HTML, CSS, Grunt, Sass, JSP, JSTL, BackboneJS and of course with jQuery to name but a few. Further technologies and frameworks include Windows 7, Netbeans, IntelliJ, Eclipse, Maven, Ant, Git, Git bash, Tomcat and Oracle DB.

July 2011 - July 2013 : Software Developer at Oracle Health Insurance

Project: OHI Self Service webapplication.

Technologies: On the frontend Java with Struts and Tiles, on the backend Spring (including Spring webservices) and Hibernate.

I also worked extensively on improvement of test coverage and code compliance of the application using JUnit, Jenkins and Sonar.

January 2006 - July 2011 : Java Developer & SOA Architect at Tripolis Solutions

Project: Tripolis Dialogue e-marketing webapplication. All SOA architecture aspects and social media connectivity.

Technologies: On the backend the latest versions of Java and Spring incl. Spring Webflow, Spring MVC, Spring JDBC, Spring AOP and Spring Social. Webservice frameworks include CXF and Axis (v1.4 and 2). On the frontend Spring MVC, JSP and Sitemesh.

Project: Tripolis SystemWeb.

Technologies: Grails / Groovy and Wicket.

May 2005 - January 2006 : Java Developer at Veritate

Project: Veritate Mail (existing webapplication).

Technologies: Java, Struts and Hibernate.

January 2001 - April 2005 : Java Developer at Eperium Business Solutions

Project: Intershop / Enfinity client implementations. Multiple e-commerce implementations for ECI and the Auping Match store application for Auping.

Technologies: Perl with Intershop 4, Java with Enfinity and Suite 6.

May 1994 - December 2000 : Prison guard at the Over-Amstel penal institution

prison guard long- and short-term sentenced men.

Before May 1994

Various jobs, a.o. entertainer on the island of Menorca, lock keeper at the Duivendrechtse Bridge and Groote Zeesluis in Muiden, warehouse keeper.

Education

I have done and continue to do a lot of self study concerning Java technology and various Java frameworks incl. the various modules of Spring, Hibernate, CXF as well as integration possibilities with social media networks.

In 2011 I followed a 3 day PL-SQL course at Oracle University.

In 2010 I attended a Certified SOA Architect course at SOA School, from Thomas Erl. This course was held in Hamburg and executed by SOAPark. I completed 2 exams for the modules presented there giving me the title 'SOA Professional'.

I attended the first Grails Exchange seminar in London, in 2007. This was hosted by the lead developers of both Grails and Groovy.

I attended several seminars with Rod Johnson (creator of Spring Framework) in the U.K. and the Netherlands (2006 - 2007).

Throughout the years I attended several Java seminars like Devoxx/Javapolis (Belgium) and J-Fall and J-Spring (Netherlands).

Intershop Suite 6 at Eperium(4 day course, 2004).

Java Programming Language and Object Oriented Programming at Sun, Amersfoort (4 day course, 2003).

Prison guard at the Over-Amstel penal institution (8 weeks, 1994).

Course for Application Programmer in COBOL (1988).

Mavo (1983 - 1987).

Interests and hobbies

Outside of my work I enjoy making music; I play bass guitar in my rock band August Life, piano and keyboards. I also like riding my motorcycle, currently a Triumph Tiger XCa from 2018.

Languages

Dutch (mother tongue), English (fluent), German (sufficient)

Technologies

Programming and development in general

Languages: Front-end: Javascript / Typescript. Back-end: Javascript (NodeJS), Java and Groovy. XML, XSD, JSON and WSDL as used in SOAP and REST webservices. I have also programmed in Python, Perl and PHP but have less experience in those languages.

Web- and Application-servers: Express, Ngnix, Apache HTTPServer, Tomcat, Resin, Glassfish, Jboss, Websphere and Weblogic.

Service frameworks: CXF, Spring-WS, Axis 1 and 2.

Search frameworks: Lucene, Solr

Test frameworks: TestNG, JUnit, JMeter, EasyMock, PowerMock, Mockito, Selenium, Fitnesse. On the front-end CodeceptJS, Protractor, Cucumber, Karma, Sinon.

IDE's: IntelliJ-IDEA, Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, WebStorm, Netbeans, Android Studio, Aptana Studio

CI/CD: GitHub Pages, BitBucket, GitHub, Ant, Maven 1 and 2, Continuum, Luntbuild, Hudson, Jenkins, Sonar, PCF.

Databases: MySQL, IBM DB2, Oracle XE / 8i / 10g / 11g and MongoDB.

Object Relational Mapping (ORM) Frameworks: JPA - Hibernate, EclipseLink. **NoSQL:** Mongoose for MongoDB (NoSQL; not an ORM framework).

Web: HTML 4/5, AngularJS, Angular 8+, TypeScript, Polymer, CSS, JSP, Sitemesh, Tiles, Spring Framework (incl. Spring Boot, Spring Webflow, Spring MVC, Spring JDBC, Spring AOP, Spring Social etc), Apache Wicket, Jakarta Struts, Freemarker and Velocity. Of course I am also familiar with HTML 4/5, CSS, Javascript and various javascript libraries like NodeJS.

e-commerce frameworks: Intershop 4, Intershop Enfinity and Intershop Suite 6.

Version control: Git, SVN, CVS.

Experience with various technologies

Technology	Experience
Java (incl. libraries and frameworks) / Javascript / jQuery / HTML / CSS / GIT / Maven / XML / JSON	10+ years
Angular 2+ (now Angular 9/10)	5 years
AngularJS	5 years
NodeJS / NPM	5 years
Grunt / Gulp / Brunch / Sass / Bower	5 years
Jasmine / Karma / Protractor	4 years
Typescript	4 years
ES6, ES7, ES8	4 years
Webpack	4 years
CodeceptJS / Gradle / Yarn	2 year
Sinon / Cucumber / Gherkin	1 year

Experience with various back-end technologies as described in resume

All back-end technologies described in my resume I have 19+ years of experience with.